ABHIJITH DAMERUPPALA

Bloomington, IN 47404 • adameru@iu.edu • www.linkedin.com/in/abhijithdameruppala • https://github.com/abh1jith

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly motivated and adaptable software development enthusiast with a solid foundation in Computer science and hands on experience in Programming languages such as C, Python, and R, with experience in assisting with Agile Development Methodologies.

EDUCATION

Indiana University, Luddy School of Informatics, Computing, and Engineering, IN.

Anticipated: May 2024

Master of Science: Data Science

[Relevant Coursework: Software Engineering, Advanced Database Concepts, Data Mining, Algorithms Design and Analysis, Mastering the WWW, Introduction to Statistics]

Vasavi College of Engineering - Hyderabad, INDIA

July 2022

Bachelor of Engineering

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, C, R/RStudio, SQL [ML/AI libraries: NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn.]

Web Development: HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React JS, Express, Redux, Node.js, LAMP, and MERN stack

Database: PostgreSQL, MariaDB, and MongoDB.

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux/Unix.

EXPERIENCE

Graphic Designer-Vasavi College of Engineering, Hyderabad, India [Adobe Illustrator, Canva] Dec 2021-April 2022

- Served as a Graphic Designer for Electrrico Revisita, a branch-magazine club that publishes updates every 3 months on global trends.
- Utilized my expertise in graphic design to enhance the visual appeal and readability of the magazine, creating engaging and informative layouts for each edition.

Branch Representative-Code chef executive team, Vasavi College of Engineering, India

June 2021 – Nov2021

- Fulfilled the duties of Branch Representative for Code Chef's Executive Team, as the representative of the EEE department at Vasavi College Chapter.
- Facilitated communication between the executive team and the wider college community, while contributing to team efforts to drive projects and initiatives forward.

PROJECTS

Image classification Model [CNN, K Means, Transfer Learning]

Sep 2022-Dec 2022

- Implemented a machine learning model for image classification using K Means clustering, CNN, and Transfer Learning.
- Achieved successful image classification between Cat and Dog clusters using transfer learning to fine-tune a pre-trained CNN model with final best accuracy of 95.92%

College Search Engine Web-Application [JavaScript, ReactJS, Redux]

Sep 2022-Dec 2022

- Built a feature-rich university search platform using JavaScript, ReactJS, Redux, MongoDB, HTML CSS, and postman for API testing and validation.
- Designed intuitive user interfaces and ensures seamless functionality through extensive testing and optimization.

Robin's Nest-Social Networking Website [PHP, JavaScript, HTML, MariaDB]

- Designed and developed a social networking website, Robin's Nest, with an emphasis on user experience and functionality Utilized.
- HTML, PHP, and JavaScript to create a dynamic platform, including essential features such as login and profile management.